<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.5.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-10-05T15:06:10-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Jared Johnson</title><subtitle>Tech and Public Policy are on a collision course. I'm working to mitigate the damage.
</subtitle><author><name>Jared Johnson</name></author><entry><title type="html">digital HKS: Open memo to Governor Baker about Government as a Platform</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/10/05/government-as-a-platform.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="digital HKS: Open memo to Governor Baker about Government as a Platform" /><published>2018-10-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/10/05/government-as-a-platform</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/10/05/government-as-a-platform.html">&lt;p&gt;There has been interest from your office about building government as a platform in Massachusetts. In this letter, my aim is to provide clarity on what that might entail, where you should start and how this all should be governed. Embracing government as a platform is not an incremental change. It is a fundamental shift to the way that government data is managed and the way that digital services are offered. While not a path free of issues and headaches, this journey will result in services that better serve the needs of Massachusetts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Government as a platform is an idea first expressed by technology writer, Tim O’Reilly, in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mitpressjournals.org/doi/pdf/10.1162/INOV_a_00056&quot;&gt;this 2011 article&lt;/a&gt;. O’Reilly makes the argument that government data should be treated as an asset and that investment in the infrastructure connecting that asset to the the public will lead to greater innovation capacity from both government itself and the public. Moreover, the investment that O’Reilly calls for should be guided by “platform thinking.” This means establishing a set of standards around an asset that allow for applications and services to built on top of it. These “extensions” of the platform will be better government services, made possible by easier-to-use data, but also radically innovative applications developed by the public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building government as a platform in Massachusetts would mean moving to a “&lt;a href=&quot;https://assets.publishing.service.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/60993/Martha_20Lane_20Fox_s_20letter_20to_20Francis_20Maude_2014th_20Oct_202010.pdf&quot;&gt;service culture&lt;/a&gt;,” where by 1) a portfolio of services can be accessed through a &lt;strong&gt;single portal&lt;/strong&gt;, supported by all departments but managed by a &lt;strong&gt;single authority&lt;/strong&gt; and 2) establishing a single authority responsible for designing the &lt;strong&gt;architecture and standards&lt;/strong&gt; for government data. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-single-portal&quot;&gt;A single portal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Massachusetts citizens should not have to face different user experiences across one government. Right now, &lt;a href=&quot;mass.gov&quot;&gt;Mass.gov&lt;/a&gt; is a bloated portal connecting our citizens to many different departments, all offering different experiences. Most of the services we offer operate on an island. They warehouse their own data and rely on duplicative IT infrastructure. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/drivers_license_GaaP.png&quot; alt=&quot;renew drivers license&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Portal for renewing your drivers license&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/jury_duty_GaaP.png&quot; alt=&quot;jury duty&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Portal for responding to jury duty&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not enough that we are offering these services online. We can make them cheaper, easier-to-build and easier for our citizens to use. This starts with making Mass.gov the single portal to all government hosted and supported services. Regardless of the department responsible for the content or application, a shared set of design principle should rule. Our citizens should recognize a familiar look and feel whenever using a Massachusetts digital service. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don’t need to reinvent the wheel every time a department wants to create a service. Moving to a system of shared IT services, we can reduce the burden that departments face in building services. At the same time, we can drastically cut vendor costs and increase the speed at which applications can be developed. Universal design principles and shared IT services are two of the most important pillars of a government platform. The single most important pillar, yet, is data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;architecture-and-standards-for-government-data&quot;&gt;Architecture and standards for government data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as much IT infrastructure is duplicative, so is much of the data collected by our government. This is necessary in a world where each department, and often each service, operates in its own sandbox. There are universal benefits that come with moving towards a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Single_source_of_truth&quot;&gt;single source of truth&lt;/a&gt; but the stakes for government are much higher. In order for a department to build a new service today, they must spend enormous amounts of time and money working to integrate data from a different system, if they can even get access to the other systems. This friction slows development cycles and bloats budgets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A more efficient way to share data using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/danwoods/2011/12/15/explaining-the-api-revolution-to-your-ceo/#2b9f7dee1179&quot;&gt;APIs&lt;/a&gt; can solve these problems but you first need someone to establish some standards. One of the primary responsibilities of digital services should be to set and maintain these standards so that data is usable and transferrable. Once data is made available, the process for integration into a new services should require no formal approvals. Making data more accessible can empower departments and their vendors to employ agile development processes, increasing the speed to market and citizen engagement. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;where-to-start&quot;&gt;Where to start&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fair question to ask is where to start and I have two recommendations. Given that one of the key benefits of government as a platform is the reduction of duplication, I suggest starting with &lt;strong&gt;citizen records&lt;/strong&gt;. I’m talking about names, addresses, birth dates and other information that is likely to be duplicated across systems. A useful user application to build on top of these records is a single sign on platform across all government departments. This way, citizens can use the same credentials to log on for the entire portfolio of services. The UK Government Digital Services had success integrating this with third party banks and mail carriers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/eaves_GaaP.png&quot; alt=&quot;single sign on&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;credit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@daeaves&quot;&gt;David Eaves&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another logical place to start is with the services that are currently used the most. Right now on the mass.gov website, we list “featured services” and “popular searches.” Redesigning these high traffic services could go a long way in gaining the buy in and trust from all government departments. Moreover, this buy in is essential to the success of government as a service for Massachusetts and a thoughtful governance structure will be necessary to achieve it.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;governance&quot;&gt;Governance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mentioned above that digital services should be responsible for developing the standards for government data. If you accept O’Reilly’s argument about the importance of government data as an asset, you must also recognize the power in controlling that asset. As &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@daeaves&quot;&gt;David Eaves&lt;/a&gt; warns, “whoever controls the databases controls the government.” Thus, I would recommend establishing digital services as an independent executive office separate from the other IT functions housed in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mass.gov/topics/executive-office-of-technology-services-and-security&quot;&gt;EOTSS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I make this suggestion for two reasons. First, establishing an independent executive office, with the head of digital services reporting directly to the governor, will give the team the authority necessary to hold other departments to their standards. The UK Government Digital Services team held the power to approve IT vendor contracts. This power brought them animosity from various government departments but proved critical in their rollout. That may not be necessary in the case of Massachusetts state but the lesson about the importance of independent power should hold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The independence of digital service is also necessary to prevent political actors within government from blocking the transfer or uses of data. Moving from the isolated ecosystems of today towards the open innovation that comes with government as a platform is political in its own right. Standing for innovation means establishing a governance structure where data cannot be ransomed or withheld for political gain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://projects.iq.harvard.edu/digitalhks/home&quot;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about digital HKS&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jared Johnson</name></author><summary type="html">There has been interest from your office about building government as a platform in Massachusetts. In this letter, my aim is to provide clarity on what that might entail, where you should start and how this all should be governed. Embracing government as a platform is not an incremental change. It is a fundamental shift to the way that government data is managed and the way that digital services are offered. While not a path free of issues and headaches, this journey will result in services that better serve the needs of Massachusetts.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">digital HKS: Redefining Failure with The Lean Startup</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/09/17/redefining-failure-lean-startup.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="digital HKS: Redefining Failure with The Lean Startup" /><published>2018-09-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-09-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/09/17/redefining-failure-lean-startup</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/09/17/redefining-failure-lean-startup.html">&lt;p&gt;Last fall, I had an idea to build a real estate crowdfunding startup. Along with another MIT student, I  applied for DesignX, an accelerator program based out of the School of Architecture + Planning. Only four months after starting our venture, I left the team. Frustrated with the pace of progress, I forced the team to take a trip to New York to hear from some potential users. After returning with many of my assumptions invalidated, I wanted to move on. I consider this experience a failure because I failed to lead my team down a more &lt;a href=&quot;https://smile.amazon.com/Lean-Startup-Entrepreneurs-Continuous-Innovation/dp/0307887898/ref=sr_1_1%3Fie=UTF8%26qid=1450159620%26sr=8-1%26keywords=lean+startup&quot;&gt;hypothesis-driven path (Eric Ries, &lt;em&gt;The Lean Startup&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;. We spent months ironing out the details of our business model before actually talking to customers. Our most critical assumption went untested for the entirety of our venture. It was only once we presented our model to users that we realized that we had no business at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team set out to build a platform to connect investors and developers within a community. I want to differentiate my use of &lt;em&gt;platform&lt;/em&gt; from the way that &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@daeaves&quot;&gt;David Eaves&lt;/a&gt;, director of digital HKS at Harvard Kennedy School, uses it to describe a set of rules and resources for others to build services on top off. We wanted a closed and controlled ecosystem to pool and distribute investment dollars. I assumed that cheaper financing for projects that already had community support would be a compelling proposition for developers. We built wireframes and mockups and I even started to code out an early version of this platform. We went back and forth over which city to start in and searched for project sites. The comfort of being in accelerator program with funding made me believe we were doing everything right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost none of our research had been with our potential users. In our platform model, we had two groups of users: investors and developers. To our credit, we spoke with a dozen or so people who expressed interest in signing up on our platform as an investor. The other side of the market was completely unclear to us. When my comfort wore off, I started to have doubts. I wanted to learn from developers. What did they want? How could we design around them to make our platform a no-brainer to use? Our team booked a trip to New York, where we had a few real estate contacts, in search of these answers. We learned that developers, in large, didn’t want to work on someone else’s idea. Even cheap financing didn’t make these projects more attractive than one of their own. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This insight was knowable from the beginning. A more hypothesis-driven process, like Reis talks about &lt;em&gt;in The Lean Startup&lt;/em&gt;, could have helped. We could have translated our assumptions into falsifiable hypotheses. For example, we could have exposed our assumption about our value proposition into a target number of developers that we could sign up. We wouldn’t need to build the platform to get these sign ups. A simple landing page with a description and a sign up form would be enough to gather this insight. We could also do this in person with a simple concept statement. Very early in this process, we could have surfaced the fact that our venture would not work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In response to this invalidation, we could have adapted to what we learned. We felt exhausted and disillusioned by failure but a key component of a lean process is redefining failure. The goal is to learn and adapt. I am still confident in the consumer demand for smaller real estate investments. A lean process could generate new hypotheses about how to incentive a supply of investment opportunities. If our team were to generate more assumptions and test them, we could have increased our odds of success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lean and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.agilenutshell.com/agile_vs_waterfall&quot;&gt;agile methodology&lt;/a&gt; is often contrasted with the “waterfall” approach. Waterfall is common in the world of project management and emphasizes planning at the expense of testing. Testing comes last in the waterfall approach and is often where shortcuts are taken. While I have been a part of teams that employed waterfall, I am more susceptible to what Ries refers to as the “Just Do It” approach. This is, as the name suggests, when an entrepreneur expresses a bias for action at the expense of direction and goals. It is important for me to remember that structure is not my enemy. In fact, a little structure will empower my bias for action and give purpose to this activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lasting takeaway for me is that process is necessary to avoid, as Reis states, “offering a product that no one wants.” And who better to tell you what the consumer wants than the consumer themselves?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://projects.iq.harvard.edu/digitalhks/home&quot;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about digital HKS&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jared Johnson</name></author><summary type="html">Last fall, I had an idea to build a real estate crowdfunding startup. Along with another MIT student, I  applied for DesignX, an accelerator program based out of the School of Architecture + Planning. Only four months after starting our venture, I left the team. Frustrated with the pace of progress, I forced the team to take a trip to New York to hear from some potential users. After returning with many of my assumptions invalidated, I wanted to move on. I consider this experience a failure because I failed to lead my team down a more hypothesis-driven path (Eric Ries, The Lean Startup). We spent months ironing out the details of our business model before actually talking to customers. Our most critical assumption went untested for the entirety of our venture. It was only once we presented our model to users that we realized that we had no business at all.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My favorite albums of 2017, with tweets!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/12/06/favorite-albums-of-2017.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My favorite albums of 2017, with tweets!" /><published>2017-12-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/12/06/favorite-albums-of-2017</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/12/06/favorite-albums-of-2017.html">&lt;p&gt;I made a list of my favorite albums of 2017 and accompanying tweets. Direct your complaints to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/yungpanko&quot;&gt;@yungpanko&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;25-giggs---wamp-2-dem&quot;&gt;25. Giggs - Wamp 2 Dem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;considering the unfortunate souls who cannot recognize the fact that giggs is the best rapper&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jared Johnson (@yungpanko) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/yungpanko/status/919325723235639298?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;October 14, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;24-trippie-redd---a-love-letter-to-you-2&quot;&gt;24. Trippie Redd - A Love Letter to You 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;trippie redd dropped a classic? 😯&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jared Johnson (@yungpanko) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/yungpanko/status/916275457103888384?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;October 6, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;23-lil-uzi-vert---luv-is-rage-2&quot;&gt;23. Lil Uzi Vert - Luv is Rage 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;an essay in which a line is drawn from kanye&amp;#39;s relationships with amber n kim to the line on uzi&amp;#39;s album &amp;quot;i took you out of them fur boots&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jared Johnson (@yungpanko) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/yungpanko/status/906288446423085058?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;September 8, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;22-gucci-mane---droptopwop&quot;&gt;22. Gucci Mane - Droptopwop&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;gucci mane back to making fire music and y&amp;#39;all back to ignoring him it seems&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jared Johnson (@yungpanko) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/yungpanko/status/879391656591712257?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 26, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;21-chief-keef---thot-breaker&quot;&gt;21. Chief Keef - Thot Breaker&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;fav part of the chief keef album is when he asks a girl &amp;quot;what do u eat, what&amp;#39;s your favorite color? do you like d-rose or do u like butler?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jared Johnson (@yungpanko) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/yungpanko/status/879314747744804864?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 26, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;20-lil-peep-rip---come-over-when-youre-sober&quot;&gt;20. Lil Peep &lt;em&gt;(RIP)&lt;/em&gt; - Come Over When You’re Sober&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;i&amp;#39;m like 30 music things behind but the peep album is good&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jared Johnson (@yungpanko) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/yungpanko/status/901280627156275200?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;August 26, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;19-stormzy---gang-signs--prayer&quot;&gt;19. Stormzy - Gang Signs &amp;amp; Prayer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;skepta is gucci. stormzy is quavo lmao i hate this analogy already but gotta get these tweets off&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jared Johnson (@yungpanko) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/yungpanko/status/843237112463998976?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;March 18, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;18-21-savage-offset-and-metro-boomin---without-warning&quot;&gt;18. 21 Savage, Offset, and Metro Boomin - Without Warning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;it really took a 21 savage tape and cardi b for y’all to realize offset was always the best migo&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jared Johnson (@yungpanko) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/yungpanko/status/933547564313571328?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;November 23, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;17-drake---more-life&quot;&gt;17. Drake - More Life&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;blem (adj.) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;definition: it mean what drake said&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jared Johnson (@yungpanko) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/yungpanko/status/919360558301941760?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;October 15, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;16-yung-nudy---nudy-land&quot;&gt;16. Yung Nudy - Nudy Land&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;haven’t tweeted about the young nudy album yet but it’s the only album i listen to&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jared Johnson (@yungpanko) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/yungpanko/status/915972534503272448?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;October 5, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;15-jay-z---444&quot;&gt;15. Jay Z - 4:44&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;paul ryan would enjoy this jay z album&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jared Johnson (@yungpanko) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/yungpanko/status/880777306763145216?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 30, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;14-meek-mill---wins--losses&quot;&gt;14. Meek Mill - Wins &amp;amp; Losses&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;whole TL would still be gassing the meek album if the drake thing never happened. he really came thru&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jared Johnson (@yungpanko) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/yungpanko/status/901290756719169536?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;August 26, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;13-chris-brown---heartbreak-on-a-full-moon&quot;&gt;13. Chris Brown - Heartbreak on a Full Moon&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;chris brown dropped 45 songs and 49 of them are fire&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jared Johnson (@yungpanko) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/yungpanko/status/925385699343335425?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;October 31, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;12-young-thug---beautiful-thugger-girls&quot;&gt;12. Young Thug - Beautiful Thugger Girls&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;thug&amp;#39;s vocals on tomorrow to infinity &amp;gt; every adele song i&amp;#39;ve ever heard&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jared Johnson (@yungpanko) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/yungpanko/status/878783273689862146?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 25, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;11-vince-staples---big-fish-theory&quot;&gt;11. Vince Staples - Big Fish Theory&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;we don&amp;#39;t deserve vince&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jared Johnson (@yungpanko) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/yungpanko/status/877678736929427460?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 22, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;10-youngboy-never-broke-again-nba-youngboy---ai-youngboy&quot;&gt;10. YoungBoy Never Broke Again (NBA YoungBoy) - AI YoungBoy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;an alternate universe where NBA YoungBoy is given the same praise for his art that creators of &amp;quot;high art&amp;quot; receive&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jared Johnson (@yungpanko) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/yungpanko/status/895271908152930304?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;August 9, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;9-tyler-the-creator---flower-boy&quot;&gt;9. Tyler, the Creator - Flower Boy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;tyler got a jaden smith hook? FLOWER BOY CLASSIC. ION NEED TO HEAR NOTHING ELSE&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jared Johnson (@yungpanko) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/yungpanko/status/889107806846164994?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;July 23, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;8-kodak-black---painting-pictures&quot;&gt;8. Kodak Black - Painting Pictures&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;ht&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;kodak said &amp;quot;i be money lawnjerin&amp;quot; lmao&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jared Johnson (@yungpanko) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/yungpanko/status/857361528328212480?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;April 26, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;7-future---futurehndrxx&quot;&gt;7. Future - FUTURE/HNDRXX&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;hndrxx still amazing and i&amp;#39;m still prepared to block anyone who says otherwise&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jared Johnson (@yungpanko) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/yungpanko/status/879417181473304576?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 26, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;post-seeing future perform songs off &amp;quot;future&amp;quot; i would like to revise my stance on it as an album. still too long but it&amp;#39;s p good&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jared Johnson (@yungpanko) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/yungpanko/status/862722814129967104?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;May 11, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;6-kendrick-lamar---damn&quot;&gt;6. Kendrick Lamar - Damn.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;kendrick&amp;#39;s album is good but humble is the worst song&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jared Johnson (@yungpanko) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/yungpanko/status/865354002036391937?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;May 18, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-21-savage---issa-album&quot;&gt;5. 21 Savage - Issa Album&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;i listened to issa 3 times today and offer that it is a top 5 rap album 2k17&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jared Johnson (@yungpanko) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/yungpanko/status/896178889101381632?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;August 12, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-sampha---process&quot;&gt;4. Sampha - Process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;trump doing his best to distract y&amp;#39;all from the fact that sampha still got the best album of 2017&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jared Johnson (@yungpanko) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/yungpanko/status/911680945907994624?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;September 23, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-sza---ctrl&quot;&gt;3. SZA - Ctrl&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;i still listen to that SZA album with my jaw open thinking how the hell she made it so good&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jared Johnson (@yungpanko) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/yungpanko/status/917089579408199680?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;October 8, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-king-krule---the-ooz&quot;&gt;2. King Krule - The OOZ&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;king krule album review: best walking at night album of all time&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jared Johnson (@yungpanko) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/yungpanko/status/919720678429024256?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;October 16, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-playboi-carti---playboi-carti&quot;&gt;1. Playboi Carti - Playboi Carti&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;ya mcm still tryna deny carti. they played magnolia in the club and he went to fake a phone call&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jared Johnson (@yungpanko) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/yungpanko/status/892821016749191202?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;August 2, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</content><author><name>Jared Johnson</name></author><summary type="html">I made a list of my favorite albums of 2017 and accompanying tweets. Direct your complaints to @yungpanko.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Prototyping at the IDEO CoLab</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/10/31/ideo-co-lab-makeathon.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Prototyping at the IDEO CoLab" /><published>2017-10-31T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-10-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/10/31/ideo-co-lab-makeathon</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/10/31/ideo-co-lab-makeathon.html">&lt;p&gt;This past weekend, I participated in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ideocolab.com/makeathon/&quot;&gt;IDEO CoLab Makeathon&lt;/a&gt;, where I was part of a team tasked with ideating, designing, and building a prototype in a single day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ideo-and-the-colab-makeathon&quot;&gt;IDEO and the CoLab Makeathon&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IDEO is a global design consultancy that is famous for pioneering the use of design thinking methodology in product and service design. The firm opened the CoLab offices in Cambridge, MA and San Francisco, CA in partnership with a number of different organizations across finance, technology and education and thinks of these locations as an R&amp;amp;D network. The focus of the CoLab is around designing prototypes exploring emerging technologies. Before arriving, I was told to brush up on &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/ideo-colab/quick-prototyping-tools-for-emerging-technologies-3fb56f62360a&quot;&gt;prototyping tools for blockchain and artificial intelligence&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Makeathon is an event held annually at the CoLab. The CoLab team uses the Makeathon to evaluate candidates interested in their two-week January fellowship, an opportunity that attracts “makers” from the fields of business, engineering and design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-team&quot;&gt;My team&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we arrived at the Cambridge, MA CoLab office, the 60 or so of us were organized into 14 teams. My team members were a designer who also teaches human centered design in New York, an undergraduate Mechanical Engineering major at MIT, an MBA student at Columbia Business School, and an engineer working on computer vision. Clearly, I was in incredible company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IDEO_team.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;team&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our team: Matt, Jennifer, Max, Wei and Me&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ideating&quot;&gt;Ideating&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each team was handed a brief that described their task for the day. My team’s brief discussed exploring the balance between the utility of voice interfaces and privacy. It gave an example of a voice interface in an immigrations office, where natural language processing and artificial intelligence could certainly be useful but the privacy concerns around transmitting sensitive information are weighty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading through the brief, we spent the morning brainstorming and iterating on our ideas utilizing some of IDEO’s frameworks. We filled a poster board with sticky notes, which we rearranged multiple times as we worked to focus our ideas around one solution. Before breaking for lunch, we stumbled upon an idea to integrate a voice interface in a stuffed animal and grew excited. We knew that we wanted to build something for first responders or hospitals and had discussed different ways to make critical information collection easier for medical professionals. Our pivot came when considering how kids may be less likely to tell doctors (i.e. strangers) how they are feeling. Perhaps they would feel more comfortable talking to something that looks more like their furry friends at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IDEO_brainstorming.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;brainstorming&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;An idea is born&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;making&quot;&gt;Making&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon, we started prototyping. The IDEO staff were helpful in pointing us toward some tools that might be helpful for what we wanted to build. I knew that I wanted to dig into the technical side and spent some time working to get Google’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://dialogflow.com/&quot;&gt;Dialogflow&lt;/a&gt; up and running on my local machine while some of the other team members started to work on our presentation and business case. By mid afternoon, we had a breakthrough. We were able to write a speech script on my computer and get it to load on a borrowed Google Home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IDEO_prototype.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;prototype2&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;IDEOg prototype&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;demo-time&quot;&gt;Demo Time&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the end of the day, we were able to demo a functional prototype that would respond to the user’s voice. We borrowed an old IDEO prototype, a cardboard dog named Bernard, and paired it with our Google Home to create IDEOg. Our product was aimed at hospitals who could provide kids who enter the waiting room an IDEOg. The product would ask the child some questions about how they are feeling and let them know that the doctor would soon be out to see them. The voice interface can overhear crucial details and communicate with the doctor, who is able to see a dashboard of data collected by the IDEOg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collecting information, and information from a child no less, is certainly sensitive and our team had multiple discussions on how our product would handle this responsibility. To address this, we made two key decisions. First, we decided that the product should not retain any information from the patients. Once the child is released from the hospital, the product should delete all information that it has collected. Second, we decided that the doctor is the only person who is able to see the data on the back-end and is only able to see the assumptions that the AI has made, not the raw data itself. Anything that the doctor would like to preserve, he or she must record that in the medical files manually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IDEO_prototype_with_google_home.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;prototype1&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;IDEOg at our demo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reflection&quot;&gt;Reflection&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was extremely proud of what my team was able to accomplish in one day and had a blast working with them. I was able to learn some of the frameworks used in human centered design, play around with new technologies, and tried my best to answer really difficult questions about the role that these technologies should play in future society. I would recommend future IDEO CoLab Makeathons to anyone interested in exploring emerging technologies and working on a team with incredibly talented people from a cross-section of fields.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jared Johnson</name></author><summary type="html">This past weekend, I participated in the IDEO CoLab Makeathon, where I was part of a team tasked with ideating, designing, and building a prototype in a single day.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Component Lifecycle Methods: Render Methods</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/08/14/component-life-cycle-methods.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Component Lifecycle Methods: Render Methods" /><published>2017-08-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-08-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/08/14/component-life-cycle-methods</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/08/14/component-life-cycle-methods.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been building &lt;a href=&quot;https://facebook.github.io/react/&quot;&gt;React&lt;/a&gt; projects for the last few weeks and I keep finding myself returning to the chart below (pulled from a lesson in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://learn.co/&quot;&gt;Learn.co&lt;/a&gt; curriculum). It summarizes the inputs and use cases for the four Component Lifecycle Methods related to rendering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Method&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;nextProps&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;nextState&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Can call &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;this.setState&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;componentWillReceiveProps&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;yes&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;no&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;yes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;shouldComponentUpdate&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;yes&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;yes&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;no&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;componentWillUpdate&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;yes&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;yes&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;no&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;componentDidUpdate&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;yes*&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;yes*&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;yes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Method&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Called when?&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Used for&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;componentWillReceiveProps&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;component is going to get new props&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;applying state changes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;shouldComponentUpdate&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;when a re-render has been triggered&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;deciding whether to re-render&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;componentWillUpdate&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;new state and props are being received&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;dispatching actions based on state change&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;componentDidUpdate&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;just after re-render&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;DOM updates following a render&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;* &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;componentDidUpdate&lt;/code&gt; will actually receive &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;prevProps&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;prevState&lt;/code&gt; as arguments, as the newly applied state and props can be accessed through &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;this.props&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;this.state&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And below is the order in which these methods are called, courtesy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/react-ecosystem/react-components-lifecycle-ce09239010df&quot;&gt;Osmel Mora&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/lifecycle1.png&quot; alt=&quot;render methods order&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This detail, alone, is worth a bookmark but in order to fully convince you, I shall elaborate. Let’s break down each of these methods. First up, we have &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;componentWillReceiveProps&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;componentwillreceiveprops&quot;&gt;componentWillReceiveProps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An important point to make here is that each of these methods is called &lt;strong&gt;after&lt;/strong&gt; a component has been mounted and thus &lt;strong&gt;after&lt;/strong&gt; the initial render. Our first render method is called before a component receives new props. This guy won’t save you if you forget to write a default state or send initial props to your component. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;componentWillReceiveProps&lt;/code&gt; is a method that React gives you to deal with new props without triggering a state change (leading to an infinite loop). One of my code instructors argues that &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;componentWillReceiveProps&lt;/code&gt; is the single most underutilized lifecycle method and I would agree given my own history of underutilizing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;code example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-javascript highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;componentWillReceiveProps&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;nextProps&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;){&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;setState&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;({&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;itemToBeUpdated&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;nextProps&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;newInfoToUse&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;})&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the code example above, I am using my new props to update the state of my component. This will take place before the re-render has completed and should any display elements be controlled by what has changed in state, theses changes will be displayed to the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;shouldcomponentupdate&quot;&gt;shouldComponentUpdate&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up is the odd one of the bunch, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;shouldComponentUpdate&lt;/code&gt;. This function is different from the others in the component lifecycle in that it expects to return a boolean (and defaults to true). &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;shouldComponentUpdate&lt;/code&gt; is used to tell React whether or not a re-render that has been triggered should be completed. This is useful when the developer is concerned with gating unnecessary rendering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;code example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-javascript highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;shouldComponentUpdate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;nextProps&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;nextState&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;state&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;text&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;!==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;nextState&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;text&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code example above is taken from one of my projects. I wanted to update a controlled searchable dropdown list ONLY if the text that I was storing my state changed. Any other actions that trigger a re-render in this component will be blocked by my &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;shouldComponentUpdate&lt;/code&gt; function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;componentwillupdate&quot;&gt;componentWillUpdate&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our next function, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;componentWillUpdate&lt;/code&gt; is the last method called before a render takes place. This is our last opportunity to dispatch actions, so long as they do not attempt to push changes to our component state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;componentdidupdate&quot;&gt;componentDidUpdate&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last render method, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;componentDidUpdate&lt;/code&gt; is called as soon as a re-render has completed. The primary use cases for this method are interacting with third-party libraries and resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;additional-resources&quot;&gt;Additional resources:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://facebook.github.io/react/docs/react-component.html&quot;&gt;React.Component Official Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/react-ecosystem/react-components-lifecycle-ce09239010df&quot;&gt;React Ecosystem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Jared Johnson</name></author><summary type="html">I’ve been building React projects for the last few weeks and I keep finding myself returning to the chart below (pulled from a lesson in the Learn.co curriculum). It summarizes the inputs and use cases for the four Component Lifecycle Methods related to rendering.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How I built my personal website</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/07/22/how-i-built-my-website.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How I built my personal website" /><published>2017-07-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/07/22/how-i-built-my-website</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/07/22/how-i-built-my-website.html">&lt;p&gt;Last weekend, I decided to build my own personal website and I thought it would be a helpful resource to document the steps that I took to get &lt;a href=&quot;http://jared-johnson.com/&quot;&gt;jared-johnson.com&lt;/a&gt; up and running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hosting-on-github-pages&quot;&gt;Hosting on Github Pages&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to set my website up using &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;. For those who aren’t familiar with GitHub, it’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GitHub&quot;&gt;version control repository&lt;/a&gt; for code. What this means is that developers use it to preserve iterations of their projects and applications. It’s a great tool and for those new to programming, I highly recommend checking it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok so what is GitHub Pages? GitHub offers a relatively easy way for users to host projects and personal websites to the web for free. And you’re able to manage your website using the same workflow that you’ll be familiar with from working with code projects on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start using GitHub Pages for your website, the first think you will need to do is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/new&quot;&gt;create a repository&lt;/a&gt; with your GitHub username and the extension &lt;em&gt;‘.github.io’&lt;/em&gt; – it should look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;your-username.github.io&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have this repository set up, the only file you need to create your website something called &lt;em&gt;index.html&lt;/em&gt;. I cloned my repository down locally and set my website up with it’s own directory but if these words mean nothing to you, I would recommend downloading the &lt;a href=&quot;https://central.github.com/mac/latest&quot;&gt;GitHub app&lt;/a&gt; to interface with your website repo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using a text editor like &lt;a href=&quot;https://atom.io/&quot;&gt;Atom&lt;/a&gt;, try typing &lt;em&gt;‘it’s my website’&lt;/em&gt; in your &lt;em&gt;index.html&lt;/em&gt; file and sending those changes up to GitHub using the code below if you’re using the terminal, or by syncing your changes if you are using the GitHub app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;git add .
git commit -m &quot;my first commit&quot;
git push
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now go to your-username.github.io in your browser and you should see something like this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/website1.png&quot; alt=&quot;your very own website!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your website is now live and you have the freedom to make it anything you want. Once I got to this point, I only partly felt satisfied. I have a functioning website but I have to type in the full &lt;em&gt;.github.io&lt;/em&gt; URL to access my site. Wouldn’t it be cooler if I could pull my website up with a snappy &lt;em&gt;‘.com’&lt;/em&gt; address? Well, you can be the judge of that but I knew my next step was to buy a domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;buying-and-setting-up-my-domain&quot;&gt;Buying and setting up my domain&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First thing I did? High-tailed it to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.godaddy.com/&quot;&gt;GoDaddy.com&lt;/a&gt;. Dot com domain names can get pricey and I was lucky to find &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;jared-johnson.com&lt;/a&gt; at an affordable price (Although I did opt to pay a premium to insert a dash between my name rather than purchasing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jaredjohnson.net&quot;&gt;jaredjohnson.net&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jaredjohnson.us&quot;&gt;jaredjohnson.us&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get my GitHub site to be served to my fancy new domain name, I had to complete a few more steps. First, I had to let GitHub know that I was using a custom domain. In the ‘settings’ tab of your repository, you should find a box to enter a different URL (see below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/website2.png&quot; alt=&quot; custom domain box&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After letting GitHub know to serve your custom domain, you will need to let your DNS provider (GoDaddy in my case) know where to route your URL. I found a really helpful &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@kswanie21/how-to-set-up-godaddy-domain-with-github-pages-a9300366c7b&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; by Kristen Swanson that details the steps needed to set this up if you are also using GoDaddy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;building-the-site&quot;&gt;Building the site&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As awesome as it is to own a URL on the internet that just says “it’s my website,” I knew that I wanted to use my site for blogging. By now, I know enough programming to build something from scratch that looks good but my experience has also taught me just how much work can go into maintaining something as simple as a blog. Drawing routes for all my posts, formatting my plain text and designing my site in plain HTML/CSS was starting to look like a part-time job. That was until I discovered &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll is a static-site generator built by one of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tom_Preston-Werner&quot;&gt;co-founders&lt;/a&gt; of GitHub. Ok but what is a static-site generator? This just means that Jekyll is an application that can render all of the pages of your website from plain text and a template. Jekyll uses &lt;a href=&quot;https://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/syntax&quot;&gt;Markdown Syntax&lt;/a&gt;, which is mostly plain text that renders to HTML, to tell your site what the contents of each page or post should be. It makes managing your site so much easier. With all of this said, understanding a little bit of HTML and CSS is extremely useful when using Jekyll, which I will demonstrate later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allow me to show you an example to better hammer home why this is so useful and then I’ll discuss setting up Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what the Markdown syntax looks like for my last blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/website3.png&quot; alt=&quot;markdown syntax for my post&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this where my blog post content is pulled into my HMTL file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/website4.png&quot; alt=&quot;html template&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this is rendered to my site to display like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/website5.png&quot; alt=&quot;blog post output&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t have to set up a database or write logic that tells my site how to deal with each individual post. Following the convention of Jekyll projects, I was able to get my post content rendered to my site in minutes. Pretty cool, right? Now let’s discuss setting up Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setup/Configuration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll is a RubyGem. This means that, assuming you have a version of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ruby-lang.org/en/&quot;&gt;Ruby&lt;/a&gt; programming language installed on your machine, Jekyll can be installed using the following commands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;gem install jekyll
jekyll new my-website
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should now have a new Jekyll project at ‘my-website’ on your computer. Since I already have a working site via my GitHub pages repository, I moved all of the files that Jekyll gave me into the same folder. Now is a good time to discuss what these files are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;File Structure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;# from the Jekyll official documentation
.
├── _config.yml
├── _layouts
|   ├── default.html
|   └── post.html
├── _posts
|   ├── 2017-07-02-quit-being-difficult.md
|   └── 2017-06-13-4-things-i-learned-toying-around-with-nested-resources-in-rails.md
├── _sass
|   └── _layout.scss
├── _site
└── index.html
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For simplicity, I’ve pared down the file tree example from the official Jekyll documentation. The first file that you should edit is &lt;em&gt;_config.yml&lt;/em&gt;, which is the configuration file that contains settings and variables that become available for use throughout your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;em&gt;_layouts&lt;/em&gt; folder is where your page templates are stored. I am currently only using two different templates for my site, one for blog posts – &lt;em&gt;post.html&lt;/em&gt; – and another for my home page called &lt;em&gt;default.html&lt;/em&gt;. As I mentioned earlier, these templates are just HTML files that are populated with content from associated Markdown files (where you write your plain text). Content from your posts and variables defined in your &lt;em&gt;_config.yml&lt;/em&gt; file will be available to these templates using double brackets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New posts must follow a certain naming convention (see below) to be recognized by the Jekyll logic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;# post example in _posts folder
YYYY-MM-DD-title.md
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;‘.md’&lt;/em&gt; here denotes Markdown syntax. Anything I write in these files is sent through my &lt;em&gt;post.html&lt;/em&gt; template and a ready-to-serve HTML file is generated in my &lt;em&gt;_site&lt;/em&gt; folder. In the &lt;em&gt;_site&lt;/em&gt; folder lies the magic of Jekyll. All of the HTML files, images and CSS/styling elements used in my website are copied over or generated in this folder. As you make changes to your ‘.md’ files in your &lt;em&gt;_posts&lt;/em&gt; folder, the accompanying HMTL file in the &lt;em&gt;_site&lt;/em&gt; folder gets re-generated. With GitHub pages, the only thing I need to do after creating or editing a post is pushing my commits up to my repository. It’s that easy – No part-time job necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design/Layouts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last that I want to touch on is using themes in Jekyll. Pre-made themes make it really easy to spin up a site that looks great in minutes. If you initialize your Jekyll project using the ‘jekyll new’ command, your site will come with a default theme named &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/minima&quot;&gt;minima&lt;/a&gt;. While this theme looks great, I wanted something even more pared down and swapped the theme for one called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pages-themes/minimal&quot;&gt;minimal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll makes changing your theme extremely easy. In your &lt;em&gt;config.yml&lt;/em&gt; file, you can swap out your theme for a number of options available in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://rubygems.org/search?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;amp;query=jekyll-theme&quot;&gt;RubyGems library&lt;/a&gt;. I narrowed my search by reviewing the list of themes &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/themes/&quot;&gt;supported by GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;. Each theme comes with it’s own default template for pages, so I would recommend copying this over from the GitHub repository for your chosen theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I genuinely hope that this post has been helpful and that I’ve inspired you to create your own website. Don’t hesitate to reach out to me &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/yungpanko&quot;&gt;@yungpanko&lt;/a&gt; if you have any questions about my experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;additional-resources&quot;&gt;Additional resources:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@kswanie21/how-to-set-up-godaddy-domain-with-github-pages-a9300366c7b&quot;&gt;How to Set up GoDaddy Domain with GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://yeswejekyll.com/&quot;&gt;YesWeJekyl Startup Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Jared Johnson</name></author><summary type="html">Last weekend, I decided to build my own personal website and I thought it would be a helpful resource to document the steps that I took to get jared-johnson.com up and running.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Quit being difficult and just tell me what the hell a closure is</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/07/02/quit-being-difficult.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Quit being difficult and just tell me what the hell a closure is" /><published>2017-07-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/07/02/quit-being-difficult</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/07/02/quit-being-difficult.html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;functions in JavaScript form closures. A closure is the combination of a function and the lexical
environment within which that function was declared. (Mozilla Developer Network)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great. We can all go home now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…..I’m kidding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re going to look at some code but let’s break down what this definition is trying to tell us. &lt;em&gt;“a function is a closure”&lt;/em&gt; — cool — , and &lt;em&gt;“a closure is the combination of a function and the lexical environment within which that function was declared.”&lt;/em&gt; This means that functions in JavaScript are more aware of their surrounding than functions or methods in other languages that do not have closures. JavaScript functions are familiar with the variables that exist in the environment where we create them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you employ the services of google to help you understand what a closure is, you will likely come across code examples with nested functions. There is a valid reason for this, as these functions help to demonstrate how different environments can change our closures, but the definition above explains that &lt;strong&gt;ALL&lt;/strong&gt; functions are closures. We don’t have to get fancy to explain what the hell this thing really is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my first example, I am declaring a variable, &lt;em&gt;name&lt;/em&gt;, with the value of my name. Then, I am writing a function, &lt;em&gt;printName&lt;/em&gt;, that console logs the name variable that I declared above it. If you test this out yourself, you will see that it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/qbd1.png&quot; alt=&quot;img1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may seem obvious that this works but — look closely — we never called our &lt;em&gt;printName&lt;/em&gt; function with an argument. What’s remarkable about what this function is doing is the very thing that makes it a closure. Our function was able to grab the name variable declared outside of itself, and within the global environment, to complete our operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;now-we-understand-what-a-closure-is-but-how-and-why-would-we-use-it&quot;&gt;Now we understand what a closure is but how and why would we use it?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;private-methods-and-module-pattern&quot;&gt;Private methods and module pattern&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to cover two examples where your newfound understanding of closures can help. The first is private methods. A private method in JavaScript is a function that can only be accessed through another function. A quick example is below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/qbd2.png&quot; alt=&quot;img2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, I have defined a function, &lt;em&gt;publicFunction&lt;/em&gt;, that returns another function, secretFunction. Both of these functions are closures, by definition, but only &lt;em&gt;publicFunction&lt;/em&gt; can be readily called by itself. When we try to console log our &lt;em&gt;secretFunction&lt;/em&gt;, we are told that it is not defined.
In &lt;em&gt;publicFunction&lt;/em&gt;, I have employed a syntax that will be familiar if you have dealt with objects in JavaScript. By writing the return for &lt;em&gt;publicFunction&lt;/em&gt; as &lt;em&gt;“function name: function,”&lt;/em&gt; or in module pattern, we are able to call the inner function by chaining our call, similar to how we would retrieve attributes from an object. Let’s see that in action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/qbd3.png&quot; alt=&quot;img3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JavaScript’s use of closures allows us to hide our secretFunction from the rest of our global scope and even reuse the name in other functions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;partial-application-and-currying&quot;&gt;Partial application and currying&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding closures is also important for understanding the mechanics of partial application and currying. When we pass arguments into functions that return functions, our return functions, or closures, are aware of these arguments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s examine the code below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/qbd4.png&quot; alt=&quot;img4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, I am defining a function, &lt;em&gt;multiplyNumbers&lt;/em&gt;, that accepts two numbers and returns their product. I have written this function to return another function in the case that it only receives one argument. This return function, or closure, can access the first variable that we gave our outer function, &lt;em&gt;multiplyNumbers&lt;/em&gt;, and complete our operation. At the bottom of the screenshot, you can see that both ways (passing both arguments into the outer function AND passing the first argument to the outer function and the second to the inner function) return the same result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can supply our outer function only one argument and name the resulting function (see below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/qbd5.png&quot; alt=&quot;img5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that the power of closures truly shines here. Our named methods, &lt;em&gt;multiplyByFive&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;multiplyByFour&lt;/em&gt;, were birthed by the same function, &lt;em&gt;multiplyNumbers&lt;/em&gt;. They only differ in the environment scope that they refer to. The first argument for &lt;em&gt;multiplyByFive&lt;/em&gt; is still 5, even after the creation of an additional function, &lt;em&gt;multiplyByFour&lt;/em&gt;, that takes in a different first argument. Pretty cool, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading this. I hope you’ve learned that functions in JavaScript can be more than meets the eye. Below are additional resources on closures and how understanding them becomes useful in functional programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;additional-resources&quot;&gt;Additional resources:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/javascript-scene/master-the-javascript-interview-what-is-a-closure-b2f0d2152b36&quot;&gt;Master the JavaScript Interview: What is a Closure?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript/Closures&quot;&gt;MDN: Closures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.freecodecamp.org/javascript-modules-a-beginner-s-guide-783f7d7a5fcc&quot;&gt;JavaScript Modules: A Beginner’s Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Jared Johnson</name></author><summary type="html">functions in JavaScript form closures. A closure is the combination of a function and the lexical environment within which that function was declared. (Mozilla Developer Network)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">4 things i learned toying around with nested resources in Rails</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/06/13/4-things-i-learned-toying-around-with-nested-resources-in-rails.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="4 things i learned toying around with nested resources in Rails" /><published>2017-06-13T20:19:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-06-13T20:19:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/06/13/4-things-i-learned-toying-around-with-nested-resources-in-rails</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/06/13/4-things-i-learned-toying-around-with-nested-resources-in-rails.html">&lt;p&gt;Let’s table set — what is a nested resource?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m referring to a type of routing mechanism available to use in Ruby on Rails. The &lt;em&gt;‘resources’&lt;/em&gt; syntax is a useful way to have Rails generate each of the CRUD routes for you. Take a look below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/nested1.png&quot; alt=&quot;config/routes.rb in my rails application&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;config/routes.rb in my rails application&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, in my &lt;em&gt;config/routes.rb&lt;/em&gt; file, I am using the &lt;em&gt;‘resources’&lt;/em&gt; keyword to draw routes for my &lt;em&gt;‘Artist’&lt;/em&gt; model. Now, when I run &lt;em&gt;‘rake routes,’&lt;/em&gt; I can see that the following routes have been generated for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/nested2.png&quot; alt=&quot;‘rake routes’ returns the full list of rails routes to your terminal — ‘rake’ is a ruby gem that is required for this call&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;‘rake routes’ returns the full list of rails routes to your terminal — ‘rake’ is a ruby gem that is required for this call&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If i want to expand my model to include songs, I have some choices to make. I could have Rails generate a suite of routes beginning with &lt;em&gt;‘/songs’&lt;/em&gt; for me, just as I have done with artists OR I could choose to nest these routes underneath those that I have already drawn for artists. The latter would look like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/nested3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Here, I am passing my songs resources in as a block underneath ‘artists’&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Here, I am passing my songs resources in as a block underneath ‘artists’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nested approach provides me with the following list of routes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/nested4.png&quot; alt=&quot;routes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here lies the first thing that I learned about nested routes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-the-id-is-appended-with-the-name-of-previous-model-at-each-level-of-nesting&quot;&gt;#1 The :id is appended with the name of previous model at each level of nesting.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My &lt;em&gt;‘/artists/:id’&lt;/em&gt; convention becomes &lt;em&gt;‘/artists/:artist_id/songs/:id’&lt;/em&gt; once I navigate into my song routes. Why is this syntax change important? Now when my application receives a request to any of the actions defined in my SongsController, an artist ID is passed to me in the format of &lt;em&gt;‘params[:artist_id].’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I want my &lt;em&gt;songs#index&lt;/em&gt; action to display a collection of songs that belong to the artist that I am navigating under, I will need to pass &lt;em&gt;‘params[:artist_id]’&lt;/em&gt; in as an argument to stipulate that I only want songs from the artist who’s ID matches (see below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/nested5.png&quot; alt=&quot;app/controllers/songs_controller.rb&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-the-form_for-rails-helper-method-requires-you-to-pass-in-an-object-for-each-level-of-nesting&quot;&gt;#2 The ‘form_for’ Rails helper method requires you to pass in an object for each level of nesting.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rails comes pre-loaded with a bunch of different useful helper methods, one of which is &lt;em&gt;‘form_for,’&lt;/em&gt; which assists with the routing for model-based form input.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typically, I would use an instance of a model as the sole argument in a form. When we create a new song, with the models outlined earlier, what we are really doing is creating a new song object that belongs to an artist object. Therefore, without letting our &lt;em&gt;‘form_for’&lt;/em&gt; element which artist we want to relate the form input to as well as which song, our ‘form_for’ model will not work. An example of my form for creating a new song is below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/nested6.png&quot; alt=&quot;form_For&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-nesting-can-get-out-of-hand-very-quickly&quot;&gt;#3 Nesting can get out of hand very quickly&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simple demonstration: I’m going to add resources for &lt;em&gt;‘lyrics’&lt;/em&gt; underneath my nested &lt;em&gt;‘songs’&lt;/em&gt; resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/nested7.png&quot; alt=&quot;yeah, there’s gotta be a better way&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;yeah, there’s gotta be a better way&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-nesting-best-practices&quot;&gt;#4 Nesting best practices&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;http://weblog.jamisbuck.org/2007/2/5/nesting-resources&quot; title=&quot;Nesting resources&quot;&gt;Jamis Buck’s blog post&lt;/a&gt; (also referenced in the Rails guide):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Resources should never be nested more than 1 level deep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buck’s blog post suggests an advanced method for keeping your routes and URLs from getting out of control but I wanted to highlight two quick ways that you can refactor your code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;shallow-nesting&quot;&gt;Shallow nesting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding the &lt;em&gt;‘shallow: true’&lt;/em&gt; parameter to your nested resource will define routes at the base level, &lt;em&gt;‘/songs/’&lt;/em&gt;, for four of our RESTful routes — &lt;em&gt;show&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;edit&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;update&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;destroy&lt;/em&gt;, while leaving the remaining routes — &lt;em&gt;index, new, create&lt;/em&gt;— at the nested level. So how is this useful to us?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my model, with artists and songs, we are now able to use the routes starting with &lt;em&gt;‘/songs/:id’&lt;/em&gt; to view or modify existing songs on an individual basis. Recall that songs belong to artists, so upon creation, we still need to initialize a song with an artist relationship. However, once a song is created, it doesn’t matter to artist relationship if we would like to edit or delete it. And so, we don’t need to follow a lengthy route, such as &lt;em&gt;‘/artists/:artist_id/songs/:id/edit’&lt;/em&gt; to make our changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;collectionmember-blocks&quot;&gt;Collection/Member blocks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it would not help to simplify my model, collection and member blocks can be used to create routes with specific dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading and be sure to check out the additional resources linked below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://weblog.jamisbuck.org/2007/2/5/nesting-resources&quot; title=&quot;Nesting resources&quot;&gt;Nesting resources, http://weblog.jamisbuck.org/2007/2/5/nesting-resources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/2034700/form-for-with-nested-resources&quot;&gt;Form for with nested resources, https://stackoverflow.com/questions/2034700/form-for-with-nested-resources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Jared Johnson</name></author><summary type="html">Let’s table set — what is a nested resource?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ruby Operators: Double Pipe Equals</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/05/24/ruby-operators-double-pipe-equals.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ruby Operators: Double Pipe Equals" /><published>2017-05-24T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-05-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/05/24/ruby-operators-double-pipe-equals</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/05/24/ruby-operators-double-pipe-equals.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;hey-what-does-that--mean-in-your-ruby-code&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Hey, what does that ||= mean in your ruby code?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my first blog post as a programmer, I thought it would be appropriate to explain one of the questions that I was asked during my first day at &lt;a href=&quot;https://flatironschool.com/&quot;&gt;Flatiron School&lt;/a&gt;. This is a question that I had come up about a month ago and one that led me down a rabbit hole of ruby forums and reddit posts (I’ll save you the trouble and link a few of the better sources at the bottom of this post).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The controversy behind “double-pipe equals” is centered around how the operator should be translated but I’d like to focus this post on the applications that I have found for it. So, what exactly does &lt;em&gt;||=&lt;/em&gt; do? My own definition is that &lt;em&gt;“double-pipe equals”&lt;/em&gt; is an operator that assigns a value, much like &lt;em&gt;=&lt;/em&gt; or our classic assignment operator, but will only complete the assignment if the left side of our operation returns false or nil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me demonstrate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kp&quot;&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; 4&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; 4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a set to nil, it is easy to see that setting a &lt;em&gt;“equal”&lt;/em&gt; to b using the classic assignment operator would return a with the value of 4. But what if we used &lt;em&gt;“double-pipe equals”&lt;/em&gt; instead?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kp&quot;&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;||=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; 4&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; 4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case, we get the same result. When a is set to nil (or anything that evaluates to false), the &lt;em&gt;||=&lt;/em&gt; operator functions the same as &lt;em&gt;=&lt;/em&gt; would. Let’s look at an example where a is given a &lt;em&gt;“truthy”&lt;/em&gt; value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;||=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; 2&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the example above, a retains its original value even though it has been operated on through our &lt;em&gt;“double-pipe equals”&lt;/em&gt;. This happens because the &lt;em&gt;||&lt;/em&gt; acts as a &lt;em&gt;“circuit”&lt;/em&gt; in this method. As &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rubyinside.com/what-rubys-double-pipe-or-equals-really-does-5488.html&quot;&gt;Peter Cooper&lt;/a&gt; explains,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If the left hand side of the comparison is true, there’s no need to check the right hand side.
When ruby saw that a was already assigned to the value of 2, it stopped executing our code. Where I have
found this sort of conditional assignment most useful is in iteration. Let’s iterate through an array of
popular fruits, using our ||= method to assign each of the strings to a.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kp&quot;&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;array&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;apple&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;orange&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;banana&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;array&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;each&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fruit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;||=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fruit&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; [&quot;apple&quot;,&quot;orange&quot;,&quot;banana&quot;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; &quot;apple&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can see that, after our iteration, a is assigned to the first string in our array, &lt;em&gt;“apple”&lt;/em&gt; . After a becomes &lt;em&gt;“apple”&lt;/em&gt;, our &lt;em&gt;“double-pipe equals”&lt;/em&gt; will not let anything to the right of it reassign our variable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While ruby has methods that can return the first element of an array without iteration, it can sometimes be useful to control for whether or not a variable has been assigned with a &lt;em&gt;“truthy”&lt;/em&gt; value. Below is a code snippet from one of my recent labs where I found &lt;em&gt;||=&lt;/em&gt; particularly useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;School&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;kp&quot;&gt;attr_reader&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;:roster&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;initialize&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;    
      &lt;span class=&quot;vi&quot;&gt;@name&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;    
      &lt;span class=&quot;vi&quot;&gt;@roster&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{}&lt;/span&gt;  
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;add_student&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;grade&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;vi&quot;&gt;@roster&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;grade&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;||=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[]&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;vi&quot;&gt;@roster&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;grade&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;  
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, I have defined a class, &lt;em&gt;School&lt;/em&gt;, along with a couple of methods. The key thing to understand is that by calling &lt;em&gt;roster&lt;/em&gt; on an instance of my &lt;em&gt;School&lt;/em&gt; class, I am looking to return my list of students as a hash of grades pointing to an array of students associated with each grade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets instantiate an example school and populate some students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;metro&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;School&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Metro High&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;metro&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;add_student&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Jared&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;metro&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;roster&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; {9=&amp;gt;[&quot;Jared&quot;]}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;metro&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;add_student&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Graham&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;metro&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;roster&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; {9=&amp;gt;[&quot;Jared&quot;,&quot;Graham&quot;]}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add a student to the roster of my &lt;em&gt;School&lt;/em&gt; instance, I have to pass the &lt;em&gt;add_student&lt;/em&gt; method a name and a grade. However, we can see that when I added &lt;em&gt;“Graham”&lt;/em&gt; and his corresponding grade, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;, his name was added to the existing array that was created when I added &lt;em&gt;“Jared”&lt;/em&gt;. This is the magic of &lt;em&gt;||=&lt;/em&gt;. In this case, the &lt;em&gt;“double-pipe equals”&lt;/em&gt; operator recognized that a grade key has already been added and had my add_student method used &lt;em&gt;=&lt;/em&gt; instead of &lt;em&gt;||=&lt;/em&gt;, I would have overwritten my student entry &lt;em&gt;“Jared”&lt;/em&gt; when I added another student in grade &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;additional-resources&quot;&gt;Additional resources:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rubyinside.com/what-rubys-double-pipe-or-equals-really-does-5488.html&quot;&gt;What Ruby’s Double Pipe / Or Equals Really Does&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruby-forum.com/topic/151660/&quot;&gt;The definitive list of OR Equal threads and pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Jared Johnson</name></author><summary type="html">“Hey, what does that ||= mean in your ruby code?”</summary></entry></feed>